Maz Chowdury

New York City, (213) 344-8494, maz.chowdury@gmail.com

PROFILE

To create & collaborate with like minded individuals in the industry so that our strategies and solutions can be implemented into the company for future growth, sustainability & prosperity. 8+ Years of experience in Operations. From being apart of the first 1,000 Tesla's being built and shipped in Silicone Valley. To ensuring 80K Customers received their packages on time at Amazon daily.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Mar 2022 — Present

Senior Operations Manager, Kyte.

New York City

- Currently running the #1 market globally for on time deliveries (99% on time rate)
- Ensuring 1,500+ trips have a driver attached to each trip
- Direct report to an Associate Manager, 4 fleet coordinators, & 600+ drivers
- Oversee 3 lots with a fleet of 800 vehicles ensuring operational excellence
- \bullet Partner with the engineering team to develop solutions to improve Surfer App for UI & UX purposes
- Own driver partner onboarding and training
- Schedule driver partner tasks and ensure they are executed to completion (vehicle swaps, maintenance, refueling, detailing, etc.)
- · Manage vehicle onboarding and off-boarding with our supplier partners.
- Control and valeting the parking lot to maximize operational efficiency.
- Maintain the key management system to ensure security.
- Audit and control the cleanliness of the vehicles to ensure 3rd party accountability and provide customer
 excellence.
- · Maintain the vehicle fleet so that all cars are in "rentable condition"

Jul 2020 — Mar 2022

Operations Manager, Amazon

New York City

- Coach, manage, and develop a team of 50 to 200 Amazon associates
- Communicate policies to your team and act as the primary information source for the team -maintaining compliance, consistency, and taking corrective action when needed
- Create, manage, and support recognition programs
- · Support all safety programs and OSHA compliance to ensure a safe work environment for all associates
- Ensure procedures are followed for building security and product loss prevention
- Partner with the management team to establish and maintain quality control standards
- Develop performance goals and objectives to achieve customer demand and ensure accuracy and quality

Jan 2016 — May 2020

Operations Manager, Tesla

Fremont

- Leading a team of 50-60
- Designing, developing, and implementing solutions for dramatically improving material flows through the factory using Lean Principles.
- Meeting warehouse operations financial objectives by participating in budget preparation, forecasting
 requirements, planning for capital expenditures, securing company property and assets, and analyzing and
 resolving inventory variances.
- Developing a strong team of material handling personnel through selective recruitment, thorough and
 consistent on-boarding process, training, and coaching, and identification and addressing of competency
 gaps within the team. Management of the team includes proactively planning for labor needs, considering
 production ramp up, communicating job expectations, performing employee performance and objectives
 reviews, and managing the team in alignment of company policies and procedures.
- Driving improvements within material flow by planning layout and space requirements, reducing line
 impact by ensuring material availability at picking locations, analyzing and reviewing product flow, and
 evaluating and proposing new equipment options.
- Overseeing mechanical assembly line for Tesla model cars including Models S, X, & 3.
- Analyzing company data to identity trends and performances for improvements.
- Assisting software developers and engineers with daily update reports

EDUCATION

SKILLS	Flexibility and Adaptability	Ability to Work in a Team			
	Self-motivation	Ability to Work Under Pressure			
	Conflict Resolution	Microsoft Office Word			
	Adobe Photoshop	Leadership			
	Interpersonal Skills	Microsoft Outlook			
	Fast Learner	Microsoft Office			
	Critical thinking and problem solving Decision Making Creativity Effective Time Management Leadership Skills	Microsoft Excel Analytical Skills Microsoft PowerPoint SEO SQL			
			Ability to Multitask		
			LANGUAGES	Bangla	Urdu
				Hindi	Punjabi
				Spanish	Arabic
			CERTIFICATIONS	Certified Professional Ergonomist (Tesla)	Fremont
	CPR AED certified (Amazon)	New York City			